### Curriculum Vitae / Résumé



# Gary Collins

LinkedIn: garypcollins

gary.p.collins@gmail.com

View this online



### Web Engineer

Summary

I'm a Front End developer with 5+ years of web dev experience and 10+ years of commercial and enterprise development experience. I pride myself on producing quality code using Test Driven Development with Red/Green/Refactor using Agile methodologies.

I have a passion for all things UX and Design and I believe that all software should be simple and reliable enough for my Mother to use it, while flexible and powerful enough to enable power users to do more and create more.

My core skill-set includes HTML5 and CSS3/SASS, ES6 JavaScript and TypeScript, with exposure to MVC frameworks like Knockout and React and other associated technologies like NodeJS, npm, Grunt, Mocha, Jasmine, Browserify and git.

Job Experience

## September 2013 - Present Skype / Microsoft

Software Engineer II - Level 62

Front End developer on the Skype for Web client, both at http://web.skype.com and in the Outlook and Office365 Skype integrations.

- I joined Skype as Software Development Engineer (SDE) at Level 58 and progressed through to be a Level 62 Software Engineer II.
- I first worked on the Skype Rendezvous integration for Kahuna (the old version of Outlook online) and Bing.com, a simple IM and calling App.
- Then produced the first version of the SWX (Skype Web eXperience) Bootstrapper, which then became the code for Skype for Web that is first loaded by the browser and uses an external configuration service to select which package version and configuration of Skype for Web to load
- Once the Skype for Web client was conceived, I produced and designed some of the first code in the model layer, before being a key contributor to the UI, model and service connector layers.

#### Recent highlights:

- Lead the client-side effort to transition to the new Skype Contacts services.
- Contributed to the Skype for Web modularization effort in order to enable the model layer to be used as a customized and lightweight SDK internally and, one day, open sourced for
- Began work to redesign the Bot discovery experience into something more akin to an App
- Began work to bring Skype for Web up to the Microsoft Accessibility A spec.

July 2012 - September 2013

InMobi Ltd

Senior Engineer - App Publish

- Lead UI development for the InMobi App Publish product
- Composite JavaScript application
- Built using MVC principles with Backbone.js and Marionette.js with jQuery and custom jQuery UI widgets
- HTML5 + CCS3 templates using Underscore.js and JSPs
- Java based RESTful web services back end, hosted on Apache Tomcat
- AJAX requests using JSON over HTTP

# August 2007 – July 2012 Metaflow Solutions Ltd

#### Senior Engineer

- Lead the design and HTML/CCS and JavaScript development on the Metaflow Ark and MetaServer products with Java Servlet and JSP development
- Java development of the Metaflow desktop client application, with Eclipse RCP, SWT and OSGi
- XML based transport layer communication (WBXML)
- Java web services

#### February 2007 – August 2007

Infospace

#### Core Developer

- Development on the Infospace Mobile Application framework
- Maintained APIs for J2ME and MIDP applications
- Development of the Infospace b2b website
- Worked with Apache HTTP Server and Apache Tomcat servlet container as well as MySQL Database server running on both Linux and Microsoft Windows Server 2003 RC2 servers
- Java web services

### October 2005 - February 2007

iomo

#### Porting Programmer

- Took 'finished' builds of J2ME games and made them work on actual handsets
- Fixing the bugs, resizing and optimising the code and assets for the multitude of different screen sizes and capabilities of all the Java-capable mobile handsets from manufacturers such as Nokia, SonyEricsson, Motorola, HTC and LG

### References

### Damjan Došen

Current: Principal Software Engineering Manager for Skype Consumer at Microsoft

damjan.dosen@microsoft.com

+44 (0)7920 700 695

LinkedIn: damjandosen

#### Abdellah Elamiri

Current: Senior Software Engineering Manager for Skype Consumer at Microsoft

abdellah.elamiri@microsoft.com

+44 (0)7530 579 452

LinkedIn: elamiri

# Paul Chapman

Current: Senior Technical Lead at INQ Mobile

Previous: Director at Metaflow Solutions Ltd and Senior Technical Lead at InMobi

paul@inqmobile.com +44 (0)7900 167 706

LinkedIn: paul-chapman-953b428

## Matthew Cope

Current: Director at Software AG

Previous: Senior Programmer at Infospace and IOMO

matthew.cope@metismo.com LinkedIn: matthew-cope-5418a01

## Nick Reed

Current: Director Research & Development at Software AG

Previous: Technical Manager - Games at Infospace & Technical Director at IOMO

nick.reed@softwareag.com LinkedIn: ncikr

Education

2002 - 2005

University of Southampton

BSc Computer Science - Second class honours, upper division (2:1)

### Interests

- Science and new technology
- Bleeding edge web technologies
- Design Graphic and architecture
- Gaming XBOX and PC
- Photography
- Music and DJing
- Sports Skiing, Cricket, Football, American Football, Pool, Badminton